* Offerings
    * Master’s Degree
    * Graduate Courses
* Magazine & Media
* About
* Support

Search

Search

* Solutions
    
    Funding & AdvocacyVisual Arts CurriculumLesson Ideas & ResourcesProfessional DevelopmentMove Up The Salary ScaleFurther My EducationEnhance My TeachingArt Teacher CommunityNavigating My First Year
    
    Funding & Advocacy
    
    * Funding & Advocacy
    * Visual Arts Curriculum
    * Lesson Ideas & Resources
    * Professional Development
    * Move Up The Salary Scale
    * Further My Education
    * Enhance My Teaching
    * Art Teacher Community
    * Navigating My First Year
    
    [Funding Solutions
    
    Discover various funding opportunities to support your art program.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/funding-advocacy/)
    
    [Advocacy Tools
    
    Resources to build a strong case for the value of visual arts in your district.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/funding-advocacy/#advocacy)
    
    * * *
    
    [

    Art Curriculum Evaluation Rubric](https://theartofeducation.edu/funding-advocacy/#funding)
    
    [

    Alignment to Federal Funds](https://theartofeducation.edu/funding-advocacy/#funding)
    
    [

    How to Fund FLEX + PRO](https://theartofeducation.edu/funding-advocacy/#funding)
    
    [

    The Visual Arts Advantage](https://theartofeducation.edu/funding-advocacy/#advocacy)
    
    [

    The Unique Benefits of Fine Art Disciplines in K-12 Education](https://theartofeducation.edu/funding-advocacy/#advocacy)
    
    [

    How to Advocate for Art Curriculum](https://theartofeducation.edu/funding-advocacy/#webinars)
    
    [

    Asking for Art-Specific PD](https://theartofeducation.edu/funding-advocacy/#webinars)

    #### What Do Art Teachers Need to Know About Grant Writing?
    
     Article
    
    [FLEX Curriculum
    
    Save time with standards-aligned visual arts lessons, videos, and resources for K-12.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/flex/)
    
    [Graduate Courses
    
    Design your own visual arts curriculum while earning graduate credit.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/courses/)
    
    * * *

    #### What to Look For in an Art Curriculum

    #### How Flexible is FLEX? 3 Ways to Use FLEX to Supplement Lesson Planning

    #### Diving Into AOEU Graduate Courses (Ep. 344)

    #### Find Your Fit With FLEX
    
    Shorten the time spent planning and get right into art-making in your classroom with FLEX Curriculum. It's an easy-to-use platform with thousands of art curriculum materials crafted for K–12 students.
    
    [FLEX Curriculum
    
    Access a rich library of ready-to-use lessons, videos, resources, and assessments your students will love.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/flex/)
    
    [PRO Learning
    
    Dive into on-demand PD with ideas and resources you can use immediately in your art room.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/pro/)
    
    [Magazine & Media
    
    Discover articles, podcasts, and videos to spark ideas along with insider insights for success.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/magazine/)

    #### Back-to-School Success Starts Here
    
    Explore new teaching strategies and resources to spark creativity and growth in your students. Make this school year unforgettable!

    [Graduate Courses
    
    Earn graduate credit with 30+ online courses—including 9 hands-on studio courses.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/courses/)
    
    [PRO Learning
    
    Unlock on-demand professional development created for art teachers by art teachers.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/pro/)
    
    [NOW Conference
    
    Join thousands of art teachers for a multi-day online conference covering the most relevant topics in art education.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/now/)

    #### 2025 Winter NOW Conference
    
    **January 31 – February 2**
    
    Earn 15 PD hours during this multi-day virtual event.
    
    [Degree Programs
    
    Earn a fully online master’s degree to upgrade or renew your license and increase your earning potential!
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/masters/)
    
    [Graduate Courses
    
    Explore art education topics that interest you while earning graduate credit to move up the salary scale.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/courses/)
    
    [PRO Learning
    
    Enjoy on-demand, short-form videos as you rack up PD hours and earn the raise you deserve.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/pro/)

    #### Why Art Teachers Stay: A Guide for Longevity in Art Education
    
     Article
    
    [Degree Programs
    
    Earn a master’s degree in as little as 22–24 months with ridiculously relevant courses that apply directly to your art room.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/masters/)
    
    [Graduate Courses
    
    Earn graduate credit as you dive deep into topics you love with guidance from top art education faculty.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/courses/)
    
    * * *
    
    Continuing Education Courses

    ##### AI in Art Education

    ##### Studio: Drawing Living Forms

    ##### Design Thinking for Art Education

    #### **Leverage Your Salary Schedule**
    
    Calculate the return on investment you—and your career—could see with a master's degree.
    
    * * *
    
    [FLEX Curriculum
    
    Level up your instruction and save time with ready-made lessons, resources, videos, and assessments.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/flex/)
    
    [PRO Learning
    
    Access a library of short-form videos and resources to help every art teacher at every career stage.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/pro/)
    
    [NOW Conference
    
    Join a multi-day virtual conference to keep up with the latest trends in art education and learn from thought leaders in your field.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/now/)
    
    [Degree Programs
    
    Earn a master’s degree online with ridiculously relevant courses you can apply immediately in your art room.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/masters/)
    
    [Graduate Courses
    
    Earn graduate credit and delve into the art education topics that interest you with 30+ courses to choose from.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/courses/)
    
    [Magazine & Media
    
    Learn from articles, podcasts, videos, and more to spark inspiration and advice you can use immediately in your art room.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/magazine/)
    
    [

    The Art of Ed Community
    
    Connect with K-12 art educators worldwide in a new, dynamic online space. Share ideas, get support, and find inspiration—all for free.
    
    Join Now](https://community.theartofeducation.edu/?_gl=1*155in91*_gcl_au*MTEzMzQ1NDI2Mi4xNzI2NjY5MTE0*_ga*MjY1OTY3NDM5LjE3MjY2NjkxMTQ.*_ga_0GR1NG16GD*MTcyNjY4Mjc3OC4yLjEuMTcyNjY4MzAxMy4wLjAuODAyOTc1OTg3)
    
    [NOW Conference
    
    Join our virtual conference and interact in real time with thousands of art teachers about the most relevant topics in art education.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/now/)
    
    [Graduate Courses
    
    Earn graduate credit while spending time with top art educators who are as passionate about the same topics as you are.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/courses/)
    
    [Degree Programs
    
    Form a network for life with a community of fellow art educators, top faculty, and experts through our master’s degree program.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/masters/)
    
    [Magazine & Media
    
    Tune into voices from your community with articles, podcasts, videos, social media, and more.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/magazine/)

    #### 2025 Winter NOW Conference
    
    **January 31 – February 2**
    
    Earn 15 PD hours during this multi-day virtual event.
    
    [FLEX Curriculum
    
    Enjoy unlimited access to ready-to-use lessons, complete with supporting videos and student-facing resources.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/flex/)
    
    [PRO Learning
    
    Get the tips you need from expert art teachers with access to a library of short-form videos and resources.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/pro/)
    
    [Magazine & Media
    
    Find articles, podcasts, videos, and more to guide any situation you may face.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/magazine/)
    
    * * *

    #### 10 Things You Need to Know Your First Year Teaching Elementary Art

    #### 6 Pieces of Advice NOT to Follow Your First Year Teaching

    ##### First-Year Art Teacher’s Guide
    
    In this guide, you'll find the support you need with tons of free lessons and resources for art teachers by art teachers.
    
* Offerings
    
    FLEX CurriculumPRO LearningDegree ProgramsGraduate CoursesNOW Conference
    
    FLEX Curriculum
    
    * FLEX Curriculum
    * PRO Learning
    * Degree Programs
    * Graduate Courses
    * NOW Conference
    
    [FLEX Curriculum
    
    The comprehensive, standards-aligned visual arts curriculum platform for K–12 teachers.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/flex/?utm_source=aoeu-web&utm_medium=mega-menu&utm_campaign=flex%20evergreen&utm_content=offerings-flex-learn-more)

    [Join FLEX
    
    Start your monthly subscription today](https://app.theartofeducation.edu/purchase/flex/?utm_source=aoeu-web&utm_medium=mega-menu&utm_campaign=flex%20evergreen&utm_content=offerings-join-flex)
    
    [Get FLEX in My District
    
    Let's connect to learn more about your needs](https://theartofeducation.edu/get-flex-in-your-school/?utm_source=aoeu-web&utm_medium=mega-menu&utm_campaign=flex%20evergreen&utm_content=offerings-get-flex-in-my-district)
    
    * * *

    [FLEX aligns to your state's visual arts standards
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/choose-your-state/?utm_source=aoeu-web&utm_medium=mega-menu&utm_campaign=flex%20evergreen&utm_content=offerings-flex-map)

    [Better Together: The Curriculum Suite
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/curriculum-suite?utm_source=aoeu-web&utm_medium=mega-menu&utm_campaign=flex%20evergreen&utm_content=offerings-f+p=c)

    #### Back-to-School Success Starts Here
    
    Explore new teaching strategies and resources to spark creativity and growth in your students. Make this school year unforgettable!

    [PRO Learning
    
    The only on-demand visual arts professional development platform designed specifically for K–12 teachers.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/pro/)

    [Join PRO
    
    Start your monthly subscription today](https://app.theartofeducation.edu/purchase/pro/)
    
    [Get PRO in My District
    
    Let's connect to learn more about your needs](https://theartofeducation.edu/pro-in-your-school/)
    
    * * *

    [Learn more about your state's PD requirements
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/choose-your-state/)

    #### Cultivate a Year of Learning
    
    Discover resources and support that will make this school year extraordinary. From lesson plans to professional development, we've got you covered!

    [Degree Programs
    
    Affordable, convenient, and relevant online Master's Degree Programs designed for art teachers by art teachers.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/masters/)

    * * *

    [Learn more about your state's accreditation requirements
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/choose-your-state/)

    ###### "How has your coursework or research changed your teaching practice? I regained my long-lost confidence as a 30 year at teacher."
    
    Berta N. WY, Master's Degree Alumni
    
    [Graduate Courses
    
    Relevant online graduate courses optimized for art teacher license renewal and salary advancement.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/courses/)

    * * *

    [Learn more about your state's accreditation requirements
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/choose-your-state/)

    ##### Palette Perspectives
    
    A Juried Exhibition celebrating the artistry of AOEU students!

    [NOW Conference
    
    The largest virtual conference for K–12 art teachers covering the most relevant topics in art education today.
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/now/)

    [Register for NOW
    
    Secure your spot at the upcoming conference](https://app.theartofeducation.edu/purchase/now-conference/?utm_campaign=NOW%20Evergreen&utm_source=offerings-menu&utm_medium=register-now)
    
    [NOW Interest Form
    
    Attend the NOW Conference with your visual arts team](https://theartofeducation.edu/now-in-your-school/)
    
    [Become a Sponsor
    
    Get your brand, message, and products directly in the hands of teachers](https://theartofeducation.edu/now/brand-partners/)
    
    * * *

    [Learn more about your state's PD requirements
    
    Learn More](https://theartofeducation.edu/choose-your-state/)

    #### 2025 Winter NOW Conference
    
    **January 31 – February 2**
    
    Earn 15 PD hours during this multi-day virtual event.
    
* About
* Support

Privacy Policy
==============

The Art of Education University understands the importance of protecting the privacy of our community members. This policy should answer all questions related to what data we collect when you engage with our website, what we do with that data, and what you can do if these practices do not meet your expectations.  
The scope of this policy includes our website visitors and registered users only. For information regarding data collected from and privacy protection for our students and prospective students, please see our [Graduate Catalog](https://theartofeducation.edu/courses/academic-catalog-archive/).

**What Information Do We Collect?**  
What information we collect from you depends on how you choose to engage with our website. Our website is designed for practicing K–12 teachers; therefore, we do not collect any data from children under 16 years of age.

**Who owns data collected by The Art of Education University?**  
The Art of Education University acknowledges that all personally identifiable information (PII) about students, teachers, and administrators is the property of the customers that AOEU serves.

**Website Visitors**  
We use cookies to collect information about our website visitors, including IP addresses, operating systems, devices used to access the website, browsers used, time spent on individual pages, search queries, and links engaged. By using our website, you consent to our collection of this information. If users adjust browser privacy settings to refuse cookies, they will not be able to engage with our site as registered users.

**Do Not Track (DNT) Disclosures**  
Some web browsers offer users a DNT option, which, when engaged, sends a signal to websites that users visit, indicating that the user prefers the DNT option.

AOEU’s website does not currently respond to DNT signals. Additionally, our partners may collect information about our users and their online activities over time and across our services in relation to our contract with those services. We do not obligate these parties to honor DNT signals sent as a result of user preference settings with their web browsers. AOEU uses cookies to track registered users’ journeys through the AOEU website. Cookies help us collect analytical information, such as which pages a user visits and how much time users spend on each page.  
AOEU utilizes Google Analytics and Gainsight PX for statistical analysis of our web usage. Users can opt-out of usage data being included in our Google Analytics reports by visiting [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

**Registered Users**  
Visitors who register for an account with us, sign up for any of our services or promotions, submit survey information, or otherwise knowingly submit personally identifiable information are consenting for us to have, store, and use this information according to the expectations set forth in our [Terms and Conditions](https://theartofeducation.edu/terms-and-conditions/).

**How Do We Use the Information We Collect?**  
We use data collected via cookies for statistical analysis to help us improve our site and deliver a more personalized experience. Our website visitors are anonymous to us unless they log in to an AOEU website account, or one of our subscription services. We use IP addresses to identify repeat visitors and customize visitors’ AOEU website experiences according to preferences. This data also helps us estimate our audience size and usage patterns, which contributes to better processing speed for our users.

We use personally identifiable information, such as email addresses and phone numbers, to communicate with our registered users and share updates, promotions, event announcements, and other information we assume our registered users are interested in receiving. At any time, if a registered user would like to unsubscribe from mailing lists, they may use the links provided in each of our newsletters to unsubscribe or manage communication preferences. We also may archive email messages exchanged with registered users for various purposes, including improving customer service, keeping a record of our transactions, and fulfilling user needs.

Users who want their personally identifiable information permanently removed from our databases may contact us at [help@theartofeducation.edu](mailto:help@theartofeducation.edu) for support.

**Who Else Has Access to Your Personally Identifiable Information?**  
The Art of Education University does not sell our users’ personally identifiable information to third parties.  
Various employees at the Art of Education University have access to stored personally identifiable information according to the needs of the employees’ roles at AOEU. These include, but are not limited to:

* Support services
* Marketing
* Curriculum development
* Product development
* Technology support
* Compliance
* Data management

AOEU engages with contractors, service providers, and other third parties to support our business operations. These parties are bound by contractual obligations to protect our users’ data in the same manner as our employees and are prohibited from sharing our users’ data or using it for purposes outside the scope of our contracted purposes.  
AOEU does not disclose users’ personally identifiable information without user consent or unless it is 1.) to comply with any court order, law, or legal process, including responding to governmental or regulatory requests, or 2.) required to protect the rights, property, or safety of AOEU community members.

AOEU may share users’ personally identifiable information with affiliates or successors in the event of a merger, acquisition, or reorganization, but only for uses consistent with this Privacy Policy.

**How Do We Protect Your Personally Identifiable Information?**  
AOEU is committed to ensuring that all data we collect from visitors and registered users is secure. AOEU stores our users’ information on encrypted servers and employs proprietary security mechanisms to safeguard our users’ information and prevent unauthorized access or disclosures.

Unfortunately, no data protection system is 100% secure. While we cannot guarantee our users’ security, we are committed to implementing and maintaining commercially reasonable safeguards to protect our users’ personally identifiable information.

Any additional information about AOEUs security practices can be made available upon request.

AOEU’s Privacy Policy governs users engaged only on AOEU’s website. It is important to note that AOEU’s website contains links to other websites considered to be interesting or useful to our visitors and users. AOEU has no control over data collection, management, and security for users of those websites. AOEU is not responsible for the privacy and protection of users who choose to engage these links and leave AOEU’s website. Please exercise caution, and review the privacy policies of each of the websites you visit.

**How Will We Notify You When This Policy Changes?**  
We will update all registered users of changes to our Privacy Policy via email with the email address we have on file. Non-registered users may visit our Privacy Policy page on our website. Each time we update the policy, we will include the date of the latest update.

**How Can You Contact Us?**  
For questions or concerns regarding this policy or your personally identifiable information, please send an email to help@theartofeducation.edu, or write us at:

The Art of Education University  
518 Main Street, Suite A  
Osage, IA 50461

**Your California Privacy Rights**  
The California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”) grants certain rights to our users who are California residents to access or delete the personal information that we have collected about them, to opt-out of the sale of their personal information by us to a third party, and not to be discriminated against for exercising these rights.

**Access**  
_Right to Know of Personal Information Collected_  
You have the right to request what personal information we collected, used, disclosed, and sold about you within the preceding 12 months. Once we receive your request and confirm your identity, we will disclose to you the information we have collected about you as required by the CCPA. If you would like to know more about what personal information we collect and the purpose for which we collect it, please review this Privacy Policy. We do not knowingly collect any personal information of minors under the age of 16.

**Deletion**  
_Right to Have Personal Information Deleted_  
You have the right to request the deletion of your personal information that we collect or maintain. Once we receive your request and confirm your identity, we will delete (and direct our service providers to delete) your personal information from our records unless an exception applies. Such exceptions include, but are not limited to, situations when the personal information is necessary to complete a transaction or provide goods or services to you, detect security incidents, comply with the law, and for internal uses reasonably aligned with your expectations.

**Opt-Out**  
_Right to Opt-Out of the Sale of Personal Information to Third Parties_  
You have the right to opt-out of the sale of your personal information to third parties. We have third-party cookies on our website that get access to your information to assist us with analyzing our marketing effectiveness and providing you with tailored content and advertising based on your interactions with our websites. If you would like to know more about how you can control how we collect information using cookies or other technologies, including how to opt-out of the use of certain cookies and other technologies, please review this Privacy Policy. If you opt-out of cookies and then access our website from another device, you will need to opt-out of cookies on the other device as well.

Types of cookies we use:

* Essential cookies: These help make a website usable by enabling basic functions like page navigation and access to secure areas of the website. The website cannot function properly without these cookies.
* Analytics cookies: These help the website operator understand how its website performs, how visitors interact with the site, and whether there may be technical issues.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

**Non-Discrimination**  
_Right to Not Be Discriminated Against for Exercising Your Privacy Rights_  
You have the right to not receive discriminatory treatment if and when you exercise your rights to access, delete, or opt-out under the CCPA.

This means we cannot, for example:

* Deny goods or services to you;
* Charge different prices or rates for goods or services, including through the use of discounts or other benefits or imposing penalties;
* Provide a different level or quality of goods or services to you; or
* Suggest that you will receive a different price or rate for goods or services or a different level or quality of goods or services.

**Exercising Your Rights**  
To exercise your right to access or delete the personal information we have collected about you or to exercise your right to opt-out, you may submit a request to [help@theartofeducation.edu](mailto:help@theartofeducation.edu) or call us at 515.650.3198. Once we receive your access or deletion request, we will contact you via email to verify your identity and review your request. We aim to respond to requests for access or deletion within 30 days of receiving the request. If we need more time to respond to your request, we will let you know the reason and how much additional time we will need.

If you have questions or concerns about our privacy policies and practices, please contact us at the mailing address, email address, or toll-free number listed in this Privacy Policy.

Last Updated: May 31, 2024

[Print](javascript:window.print())

#### Academics

* * *

#### Offerings

#### The Art of Education

#### Contact

518 Main Street, Suite A  
Osage, IA 50461

Main: [515.650.3198](tel:515-650-3198)  
8 a.m. – 5 p.m. CT

* * *

#### Choose Your State

#### Social

Copyright 2024 © The Art of Education University
